# JEFFREY/MORO

# **PROFILE**

I work across academia, industry, and the arts to understand our media present and to build its future. I'm a skilled collaborator, with experience in project management, grant administration, events planning, and digital outreach. I'm trained in the arts, humanities, and sciences, and I can speak fluently the languages of the classroom, gallery, and command line. In my academic work and teaching, I investigate electronic literature, interactivity and games, software studies, and the history of media forms and technologies.

- jeffreymoro.com
- **y** @jeffreymoro
- in linkedin.com/in/jeffreymoro
- **6**78.200.3951
- 11 Arnold Ave, Apt 2C Northampton, MA 01060

# **EDUCATION**

2013 Amherst College. Amherst, MA.

BA, English; BA, Theater & Dance. magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# 2013—Present Post-Baccalaureate Resident in Digital Humanities

Five Colleges, Inc. Amherst, MA

(Appointed at Smith College. Northampton, MA)

I collaborate with Five College Digital Humanities' faculty director to comprehensively administer a variety of academic programs, events, and grant-funded projects. I manage an Undergraduate Student Fellowship program, an Undergraduate Microgrant program, a Speaker Series, and teach workshops on digital media and digital project management. In short: I keep all the pieces moving so that faculty, staff, and students alike can do innovative work.

## 2010—2013 Scene Shop Technician

Amherst College Theater & Dance Dept., Amherst, MA

#### 2011 Admissions Summer Intern

Amherst College Admissions Dept., Amherst, MA

#### **SCHOLARLY & CREATIVE PROJECTS**

## 2015—Present Still Life in Digital: Black Life, Trauma, and Social Media

Collaborator, http://stilllife.mp285.com

In collaboration with Marisa Parham.

## 2015—Present The Recirculator

PI, http://recirculator.jeffreymoro.com

A web app that lets you randomly check out books that have never before circulated within the Five College library system, and learn more about the collection through data visualizations.

# 2014—Present AIRLab (Aerial Innovation and Robotics Laboratory)

Co-PI, http://airlab.5colldh.org

A hybrid makerspace and workgroup exploring applications of drones and other kinds of creative robotics in the undergraduate classroom and the world at large. Funded by Five College Digital Humanities.

# 2014—Present The\_Critical\_Is

PI, http://thecritical.is

A workgroup and web publishing concern, exploring critical issues in video games and interactive media. Funded by a microgrant from the Association for Computers and the Humanities.

# 2013—Present E.LIT / NET.ART

Curator & Organizer, http://elit.jeffreymoro.com

An introduction to and exploration of electronic literature and Internet art, comprising pop-up IRL and URL galleries, workshops, and a screening program.

# 2012—2013 No Wind Blows Against the Pines

Creative, Director & Author

A new play based on the Noh plays Pining Wind and The Sumida River.

## 2012 Two Winds

Creative, Director & Choreographer

A dance-theater piece in collaboration with Skye Landgraf & Morgan Brown.

## 2011—2013 Shakespeare on the Quad Theater Company

Creative, Co-founder & Producer

Produced crowd-funded productions of Shakespeare plays for local audiences.

## **COURSES + WORKSHOPS**

# Courses taught Media Archaeology, Climate Change, & the Digital (Non)humanities

Smith College & Amherst College. Northampton & Amherst, MA. Jan. 2016

## E.LIT / NET.ART: An Extraordinarily Brief History of Digital Literature, 1975 — 2015

Smith College. Northampton, MA. Jan. 2015

A week-long course on electronic literature and Internet art, exploring key pieces throughout the medium's history while providing students critical and historical vocabularies for engaging with born-digital work.

#### **Practicing Digital History**

Smith College. Northampton, MA. Jan. 2014

A week-long course on planning, managing, and executing digital research projects.

## Workshops led Introduction to Twitter Archiving

Sponsored by Five College Digital Humanities. Nov. 2015

## The New Rigor

Organized by Five College Digital Humanities

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. May & October 2015

A microconference (http://thenewrigor.org) on supporting and evaluating digital scholarship.

# Five College Digital Humanities Undergraduate Fellowship Workshop

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. Jan. 2015

#### Five College Digital Humanities Kickoff Celebration & Workshops

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. Sept. 2015

# **Five College Digital Humanities Student Symposium**

Smith College. Northampton, MA. April 2014

## Guest Lecturer ENGL-456: Ghosts in Shells?: Virtuality and Embodiment from Passing to the Posthuman

& TA Amherst College. Amherst, MA. Fall 2015

TA, Taught by Marisa Parham

# **ENGL-277: Videogames and the Boundaries of Narrative**

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. Spring 2015

TA, Taught by Marisa Parham

## **ARX-340: Capstone Seminar for the Archives Concentration**

Smith College. Northampton, MA. Feb. 2015

Guest lecturer, Taught by Kelly Anderson

## **ENGL-338: Shakespeare**

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. Nov. 2013 Guest lecturer, Taught by Anston Bosman

## **AWARDS + FELLOWSHIPS**

## 2014—2015 Association for Computers and the Humanities Microgrant

for "The\_Critical\_Is: Mapping New Approaches to Videogame Pedagogy" ACH Microgrants support small projects engaging computer-assisted humanities research.

# 2014—2015 Five College Digital Humanities Project Grant

for "AIRLab (Aerial Innovation and Robotics Laboratory)"

5CollDH grants support projects that cultivate the humanities and arts through digital innovation.

# 2012—2013 Pease (Lane) Research Fellowship for Creative Artists

for No Wind Blows Against the Pines

Pease (Lane) Fellowships provide financial and research support for students interested in using historical and rare source materials towards projects in the arts.

## 2012—2013 Alpha Delta Phi Grant

for "Shakespeare Film and the Media of Translation"

ADP Grants from the Amherst College Dean of the Faculty support undergraduate thesis research.

## 2011 Gregory S. Call Undergraduate Summer Research Grant

for No Wind Blows Against the Pines

Call Grants support intensive undergraduate research during summer terms at Amherst College.

## **PUBLIC PRESENTATIONS**

## 2015 "The\_Critical\_Is: Mapping New Approaches to Videogame Criticism"

Michigan State University, East Lansing, Ml. May 2015

Poster, HASTAC 2015: The Art and Science of Digital Humanities

## "Digital Humanities / Digital Projects"

UMass-Amherst. Amherst, MA. Jan. 2015

Invited talk, Applied Humanities Learning Lab

# 2014 "Lightning Talk: The Space of Mexico City"

Five College Digital Humanities. Amherst, MA. Sept. 2014

Five College Digital Humanities Kickoff Celebration

# "Undergraduate Digital Humanities, Three Ways"

NERCOMP. Norwood, MA. April 2014

Invited talk, Emerging Digital Scholars: Undergraduates and Digital Humanities

## 2013 "After the End: Dissolving No Wind Blows Against the Pines"

Amherst College. Amherst, MA. April 2013

Panel, Amherst Explorations: A Celebration of Student Research and Creative Work

# "Shakespeare Film and the Media of Translation"

Smith College. Northampton, MA. February 2013

Talk, Five College Film Studies Undergraduate Conference

# **SKILLS**

WebDev HTML, CSS/SASS, PHP, cPanel, twarc (Twitter archiving), CartoDB (Geographic

mapping), Jekyll (Static website generation)

## **Currently learning**

Javascript, Twitter API, D3.js (Data visualization)

# Software Social Media & Brand Management

Twitter, Facebook, Tumblr, Rebelmouse, Google Analytics

## **Around the Office**

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Apple iWork (Pages, Numbers, Keynote),

Google Apps (Docs, Sheets, Slides), Mailchimp, Formstack, Trello, Slack

## **Presentation & Media Production**

Camtasia, iMovie, Prezi

# **Project Management**

Git/GitHub

CMS Wordpress, Drupal, Moodle, Tumblr

And also Public speaking, Lessac voice training, Improvisational theater, Stage management,

Scenic design, Theater direction, Keyboard instruments (Piano, Synthesizer, Melodica)

# REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

PORTFOLIO, BLOG, AND MORE AT HTTPS://JEFFREYMORO.COM